MAHEDI KAISER

http://mahedikaiser.com mahedi.kaiser@gmail.com 347.925.4458

SUMMARY

Software engineer with over 5 years of experience and a track record for optimizing business processes through automation and innovation. Experience working in corporate and startup environments. Performed all roles in development including front-end, back-end, deployment/server management, and interfacing with business. A highly adaptable, passionate learner with a strong work ethic.

SKILLS

Web Development ReactJS, AngularJS, NodeJS, JQuery, Bootstrap, WordPress, Weblogic, Webpack,

HTML, SASS, CSS

Programming Languages Java, Python, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL

Frameworks & Technologies Springboot, SQLAlchemy, Elasticsearch, Linux, JUnit, Cucumber, REST

Tools Git, SVN, Eclipse, Intellij, Android Studios, Jenkins, Postman, Microsoft SQL Server

Operating Systems Windows, Linux, Mac OSX

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer New York, NY September 2018 – March 2019
Bombfell (Startup)

Payment System Rewrite (September 2018 – March 2019)

• Saved the company an average of 10% per refund transaction by fixing bug in refund process

• Refactored **python** code for payment system and implemented test framework to improve code reliability Pagespeed Optimization (February 2019 – March 2019)

- Improved load time and search ranking by increasing Google Pagespeed score by 70 points (out of 100)
- Optimized webpack bundling using commons chunks and compression plugins
- Reorganized page structure and lazy-loaded below-the-fold contents using AJAX and JQuery events

Security & Authentication (December 2018 – February 2019)

- Implemented Multi-factor Authentication for internal accounts using **totp** authentication
- Made accounts more brute-force resistant by implementing bcrypt password hashing

Bombfell Shop Launch (September 2018 – December 2018)

- Coordinated with Product Manager, Stylists, and 4 other developers to launch ecommerce shop in 2 months
- Wrote python code to search, sort, and cache shop items based on various filters and user preferences
- Developed multiple React components for shop pages

Custom Reporting Calendar (February 2019 – March 2019)

 Improved business utility of reports by designing and implementing custom calendar API using python and SQLAlchemy based on Nation Retail Federation calendar and internally defined reporting periods

Software Engineer Detroit, MI June 2016 – September 2018

General Motors

Salesforce Rewrite Project (January 2018 – April 2018)

- Rewrote Salesforce APIs as in-house Springboot microservices to extend availability of services
- Collaborated with a team of 15 developers and architects to make microservices work together seamlessly
- Wrote comprehensive unit tests & integration tests to ensure code reliability and maintainability

Data Setup & Diagnostics Tool (February 2017 – September 2018)

- Cut defect resolution and data setup times by 30% by eliminating bottlenecks in the process
- Collaborated with a single teammate to design, develop & deploy the tool in under 6 months
- Used AJAX and self-written AngularJS plugins to provide fast, smooth, and intuitive user experience
- Handled all DevOps related tasks including deploying application to WebLogic, implementing single sign on, setting up Elasticsearch pipeline, and writing cron jobs to manage memory and monitor system health

Test Automation (June 2016 – September 2018)

- Responsible for creating automated tests for new Salesforce REST APIs using JUnit & Jenkins
- Improved readability and business utility of unit test results by migrating to Cucumber
- Minimized build failures by collaborating with multiple teams to resolve defects

MAHEDI KAISER

http://mahedikaiser.com mahedi.kaiser@gmail.com 347.925.4458

EDUCATION

Lehman College | BSc: Computer Science | GPA: 3.8

Dean's List (Fall 2014 – Spring 2015)

Class of June 2016

ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES

Founder & Instructor Bronx, NY January 2019 – Present

Fullstack Engineering Bootcamp

 Developed and taught a comprehensive curriculum for fullstack development at my local community center aimed at anyone interested in learning software engineering

Mentored a wide range of students ranging from high school to post-college

Academic Excellence Chair

Bronx, NY

January 2016 - March 2016

December 2014 – February 2015

National Society of Black Engineers

Organized workshops and study groups for computer science classes offered by Lehman college

Hosted resume reviews and interview preparation workshops for students seeking jobs and internships

2nd Place Winner Boston, MA March 2016

National Google Hackathon

• Worked with a team of 5 to create an android app to help drive up adoption rates by connecting prospective adopters with foster care children

1st Place Winner Bronx, NY October 2015

State-Wide NSBE Hackathon

• Worked with a team of 5 to create a mobile & web solution to connect people who need to give away their pets with prospective adopters with the purpose of keeping them out of kill shelters

Independently developed a web app for the project using **JavaScript** to dynamically filter & display search results in addition to a second webpage to serve as a demo for the application

Web Developer New York, NY March 2016 – June 2016 **LSAMP**

Designed, developed, tested and deployed various components of the ProjectSTEM platform using PHP,
 JavaScript, HTML, CSS and WordPress

Created user dashboard using AdminLTE framework

Java Game Developer Bronx, NY

Independent Project

 Independently developed a video game to give children a fun way to learn their multiplication consisting of over 1.600 lines of code

PUBLICATIONS

Mathematics Researcher & ProgrammerBronx, NYOctober 2015 – January 2016

CUNY- Research Foundation

- Researched computational optimizations to continuous mean calculations in 5-dimensional sample space with direct application to mapping optimal evolutionary history in phylogenetic trees
- Researched computational complexity of determining similarity between the given network graphs and trees
- Worked intensively with a small group of CS, Mathematics, and Biology students
- Wrote **python** scripts to test proposed solutions
- Published research in the Bulletin of Mathematical Biology and arXiv: https://arxiv.org/abs/1602.02739